

#### **SUMMARY**

A multi–skilled developer with hands–on experience in scripting powerful set of web technology tools and design. Passionate about problem solving, and conceptualizing. Open to exploring exciting full–stack development opportunities in startups and companies with scale.

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

DATE OF BIRTH: 03 April 1992

GENDER: Male

ID NUMBER: 9204036100344 LANGUAGE: siSwati, English

#### CONTACT

PHONE:

+268 79 180 714

#### **ALTENATIVE PHONE:**

+27 67 098 0127

#### **EMAIL**

simosakhenkosi@gmail.com

## **HOBBIES**

Learning
Exploring/ Travel
Running/ work-out/
Meditation

# SIMOSAKHE DLAMINI

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio | AngelList | Gmail

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Front–End:** Vanilla JavaScript, React and Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI), and SEO.

**Back–End:** Ruby, JSON (XML, AJAX, and Web APIs), Node.js with Express.js, Mongo DB with Mongoose.

**Tools & Methods:** Linux, Git and GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Microsoft Office.

**Professional:** Remote Pair Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

#### **EDUCATION DETAILS**

#### Microverse

2021 - 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full–stack development while simultaneously developing projects with JavaScript, React and Redux, APIs, Ruby, Rails and Databases.
- Developed skills in remote pair–programming using GitHub, industry–standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

# FreeCodeCamp

2018 - 2021

Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Responsive Web Design (HTML, CSS, Flexbox, CSS Grid)
- Front End Libraries (React, Redux, Sass, Bootstrap, ¡Query)
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (JavaScript)
- Ruby and Databases (Ruby)
- APIs and Microservices (Node.is, Express.is, databases)
- Information Security and Quality Assurance (Chai, Helmet.js, BCrypt, Passport.js)

## **Mathews Phosa College**

National Senior Certificate – Bachelor's Degree

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Microverse Enterprise Inc. [Remote]

January 2022 – Present

Position: Technical Support Engineer

#### **Duties:**

- Provided technical support remotely to junior international web developers through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall app performance.
- Provided suggestions on maintaining app development best practices, well documentation, high standards, and professionalism.

# Microverse [Remote]

September 2021 – October 2021 Position: Mentor (Volunteer)

#### **Duties:**

- Mentored junior web developers by providing technical support remotely through platforms like Slack, WhatsApp and GitHub.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to sustain longevity in the program.
- Carried out weekly questionnaires to get statistics on student weekly progress.

# NKOSI imperial Digital Solutions [The Reeds, Centurion]

February 2019 - 2021

Position: Self Employed Web Developer

#### **Duties:**

- Interfaced with clients to identify business requirements for business proposals.
- Created an SPA website for DMH Do My Hair Salon for product and services.
- Designed flyers for DMH Salon, THE LOCAL BAR, and product designs for EDEN CHOICE oats, soya milk, Himalayan salt and granola.
- Created fun command line interface (CLI) board games with Ruby.

# HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

November 2018 - Present

Position: Full Stack Web Developer

**Binger:** Displays a list of popular TV shows that aired in different networks mainly in US, Canada, and the UK. Users can search, comment, like, and filter their favorite shows based on genre.

- Built with Webpack, JavaScript, TV- maze API, Involvement API, and CSS.
- Preview: <u>Binger</u>

**SpaceX Traveler's Hub:** Displays a list of all available SpaceX Rockets, Missions, and My Profile section lists all reserved rockets for booked space missions.

- Built with React, SpaceX API, and CSS.
- Preview: SpaceX

**Forex Market:** Displays a list of popular forex pairs real-time prices, stocks, cryptocurrencies, and ETF shares.

- Built with React, Financial Market API, and CSS.
- Preview: Market

# Casa Bella [Loftus Park – Woodlands]

May 2018 – October 2020 Position: Front Ambassador

# KOI [Lynnwood Bridge – Menlyn Maine]

September 2015 – April 2018 Position: Front Ambassador

## **Duties:**

- Utilized Pilot restaurant software for sales, inventory and purchases.
- Demonstrated genuine customer service while greeting and establishing rapport with guests.
- Handled +-R 20 000 cash on a daily basis, which built trustworthiness and loyalty with owners.
- Closed out cash register with 100% accuracy and prepared sales reports.
- Up sold daily specials and promotions and exceeded daily sales goals.